

# Leandro E. Colombo Viña

Professor // Developer



9 Octubre 1981



Larrea 910 8°D, CABA



+54 9 11 3001-5328



http://leo.bitson.com.ar



colomboleandro@bitson.com.ar

# About me ——

Over the last 13 years I've been working on Education and since 2013 I've founded BITSON, with other IT professionals, our own democratic & cooperative enterprise. In BITSON we develop free software and hardware, mainly with access control turnstiles and web applications. I've gained experience in every field related to web applications development.

# Frontend Backend DevOps Linux REST APIs

Entrepreneurship\*3 Teaching\*4 Time Management\*4 Analyst\*5

Python

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

### [Interests]

I'm a FLOSS enthusiast. I've been using Free and Open Source Software since 2009. Promoting, attending, participating and organizing events related to FLOSS. I work using the industry best practices like standard coding styles, git-flow, SCRUM, TDD and many others.

### **Education**

	in progress	
2014-2015	Computer Science Teacher	INSPT-UTN
2011-2014	Applied Informatics Grade point average: 9.29. National flag bearer 2013	INSPT-UTN
2008-2008	Instructor	CFP 34
1995-2000	Electronics Technician	Pío IX (A-66)

**UNLa** 

### Courses & Certifications

since 2017 Digital Technologies for Education

2016	Scrum Grand Master. SCEU-FRBA-UTN
2015	Digital & Social Media Operator. FUNDESCO, Ministry of Labor
2015	Remotee worker. FUNDESCO, Ministry of Labor
2014	Linux Certified Security System. Carrera Linux Argentina
2013	C Expert. Carrera Linux Argentina
2012	Project Management Executive Program. SCEU-FRBA-UTN
2011	Linux System Administrator Expert. Carrera Linux Argentina
2008	Multimedia products creation. CFP 34

2008	Multimedia products creation. CFP 34	J .	
Experience			
2014-hoy	Business Development Manager, Founding Par Project Manager. Software & Hardware deve Trainning.http://www.bitson.com.ar/		
2010-hoy	Associate Professor Teaching in the career of Systems Analysis.	IFTS18	
2011-2014	Consultant Networking. GNU/Linux System administrationing.	freelance on. Professional Train-	
2007-2015	Instructor Programming with Python. GNU/Linux BaGNU/Linux. Educational Resources for teac 101.		
2010-2014	Community Manager Google Apps for Educations administrator & s	CFP34 ocial media.	
2004-2014	SysAdmin / Teacher	Pío IX	
2000-2004	Laboratory technician	Celtronics SRL/IMD SRL	

## Other information

other information			
2016	Organizer Python Conference Argentina, Bahía Blanca.		
2015	Founding Partner & Treasurer Python Argentina NGO.		
2014-2015	Speaker at FLISOL http://bitson.com.ar/flisol/git		
2014	Salesian Cooperators Center Manager.		
2010-2012	Conference on Educational Technologies		
2011	Course Continuing Education Professional Technical Education -		
2008	DGEGP Digital Reflex Photography, Digital edition.		